Let's step away from a database server for just a
moment and talk more about relationships between
tables. Relationships should be planned before
a database is ever built. One way to organize
relationships is to create an entity relationship
diagram (ERD). An ERD will show, for a database,
relationships that should be established or are
established between entities. Some ERDs only show
entity names, but most show the columns used in
relationships, as we see with this portion of an
ERD for the AdventureWorks database. I do not have
all the tables or the columns in each table listed
here as this topic's emphasis is simply to learn
what an ERD is and its role in database design.
Note that the primary key field is indicated for
all three of these tables, which is the hallmark
of a well-built ERD. Also, we see lines drawn
between columns used in relationships. Again,
this should be built before the actual database
is built so that a database design is clearly
known and can be adjusted if necessary before
the database building process commences.